有些故事的走向和结局会重新定义一个行业
There are certain stories that end up defining an industry.
在这些故事中也传唱着 我们来自哪里
Stories we tell ourselves about where we come from,
我们是谁 我们正在做什么
who we are, what we do.
上一集中 我们追溯了 Linux 开源技术的崛起
Last episode, we tracked the rise of Linux , an open source technology.
但这一集我要讲的 是紧接着发生的故事
This story though this one's about what happened next
操作系统之战结束后 开发者们成为了战争争夺的对象和核心
After the os wars, developers were front and center.
在那个新的战场 开发者们将要重塑自己的工作
And that new prominence meant they were going to reinvent their jobs.
本集播客 我们将深入了解以开发人员为核心
This episode, we'll learn how a focus on the developer
产生的一种全新的软件开发方法论
brought about an entirely new methodology for software development
这种新颖的工作流程
And how that new approach to workflow
产生了哪些远超我们屏幕上显示的代码所能控制的 意想不到的事情
is having an unexpected impact far beyond the action on our screens
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek
欢迎收听红帽的原创播客
this Command Line Heroes,  an original podcast from Red Hat.
《代码英雄 第三集 敏捷革命》
Episode three, The Agile Revolution.
今天的故事始于 2001 年 2 月
Today's story begins in February 2001,
发生在美国犹他州的滑雪小屋里
and it's set at a ski lodge in Utah.
我们面前有个小屋 眼前是松树梁
We turned up at a lodge, you know, the pine beams and the
壁炉 还有进入屋子的小门
fireplace, and the entry way.
我们前一天晚上到达这里时
We got there the night before
然后基本上只是围坐在一起
and we basically just sat around
讨论谈我们准备探讨的内容
and talked about what we're going to talk about.
紧接着第二天 我们都起床
And then next day, we turned up.
并来到了预定的会议室
and we'd reserved a meeting room.
先把桌子移到边上去
We took the tables and moved them out to the edge
然后将椅子摆放成一圈 确切地说是一个椭圆
And we just put the chairs in a circle, or an oval
这样一来我们就可以面对面交流
so you know we could basically be facing each other and
一定程度上也让人感觉到可以敞开心扉 畅所欲言
some up more open
Dave Thomas 和其他的 16 个人 在那个冬天集聚在雪鸟滑雪场
That was Dave Thomas, Dave and 16 others got together at Snowbird Ski Resort that winter.
但是他们的目的并不是滑雪
Not to ski,
而是探讨在 90 年代开发者的世界所面临的问题
but to talk about what was wrong with the developers world in the 1990's.
在这里我用“探讨” 但实际上用“辩论”更准确
I say talk, but argue might be more like it.
他们最初是在 面向对象编程 语言及系统 ( OOPSLA ) 的会议上认识的
They had originally met at a conference called OOPSLA,  Object-Oriented Programming, Languages and Systems.
实际上正是那次会议
and it was actually at that conference
让他们意识到当前的软件开发方式很混乱
that they all agreed that creating software was messy.
只是对于该怎么办没有达成一致
They just hadn't agreed on what they should do about it.
所以此次在雪鸟山上的开会
So, the meeting on the mountain at Snowbird,
试图寻找 解决这个问题的方法
that was where they were going to try and nail down a solution to that problem.
那么究竟是这个问题具体该怎么描述？
And what was that problem exactly?
于是我询问 Dave 开发人员之前的使用方式到底出现了什么问题
I asked Dave what was wrong with the way developers used to do things
所以 我不知道…你有没有装饰过房间
So, have you ever ... I don't know, decorated a room
我有
I've tried.
好 如果我先告诉你
Or had ... Okay. So if I said to you up front okay
“我想让你坐下来 然后给你一张白纸
"I want you to sit down please here's a piece of paper
接着我希望你能描绘下
and I want you to specify exactly
这个房间完成后大概的样子 ”
what this room should look like when you're finished right
可以想象吗？
Could you do that?
实际上 我的办公室就是这么布置出来的
Actually, I did this for my own office.
首先 我画了一个简单的草图 然后加上一些修饰
I tried making up a little sketch and a little rendering and
最后把所有架子摆放在我觉得合适的位置
putting all the shells where I thought they would be
不过这种方式没有真正起到作用
it didn't really work
我的计划也没有实现
though it didn't end up the way that I planned
但是 即使你尝试了这种方式 你都做了什么？
But, even if you do that, what do you do?
先把架子放起来 然后说
You put this shells up, and you go
“哦…这样放不行 因为会挡道 ”
"Oh that's not gonna work because the door is gonna get in the way
所以 你又紧接着把架子移到其它地方
so you move the shelves somewhere else, or you
“你知道吗 我真的不能把地毯放在那里
say you know I can't really put carpet there
因为我的椅子脚会陷进去 ”状况频发
because my chair is gonna get stuck on it." Whatever it might be.
遇到未知的情况 你总需要一种“迭代”的方式去应对
You always are going to iterate whenever it involves any unknowns at all
人类的大脑无法准确地对现实世界的发展进行预判
The human brain is just not up to modeling the real world accurately enough
从而提前预知哪里需要改变
to be able to know what it wants up front
所以 软件开发也是一样的
So, software development is the same
人们不知道他们的需求会怎么改变 对吗？
People don't know up front what they want. Right?
我经历过太多这样的情况
And the number of times where I have gone through that process,
当我从客户那里拿到了详细的要求
where i've got a spec from a customer
然后我已经很好地完成了每一条细则
and I have implemented it pretty much identical to that spec.
但却总是吵得不欢而散 “这不是我们想要的 ”
It gets to the end, and they go, "But that's not what we wanted."
但我想说的是 “这就是你要求的啊 ” 他们说 “是的
And you go, "But that's what you asked for." And they said, "Yeah but that's not what I meant." You know?
但这不是我的意思 ”
but that's not what I meant
你懂这种情况吗？
you know
所以说 理想情况是  你可以详细说明流程的每一步
So, this whole process that you can specify,
然后通过非常机械的步骤就可以完成一切
and then move through some mechanical sort of steps, and then at the end you're done.
是啊
yeah
但是在软件行业可行不通
Doesn't work in software.
这种方式不适用于有任何模棱两可的情况
It doesn't work in anything where there is ambiguity.
也不适用于需要判断的情况
It doesn't work in anything where there is some degree of judgment.
就像任何艺术尝试一样
Almost like any quote artistic endeavor
这种方式就是行不通
it's just not going to work.
总是缺失了关键的一步：反馈
There always has to be feedback, and that was the missing step.
也许
So, maybe
你已经听说过上世纪 90 年代的软件危机
you've heard of the software crisis that ran through the 1990s
当时的软件开发一团糟
Software development at the time was just a mess.
相比于开发软件的费用 公司在修复软件上的钱花的多得多
Companies were spending more money fixing software than they were creating it in the first place
与此同时 你我这样的开发人员进退不得
And meanwhile, developers like you and me we were log jammed
有时候 我们每隔好几年时间才能推出新的软件
In some cases, we could only put new software out every few years
我们疲于应付这些缓慢 陈旧 瀑布式开发的工作流程
We were stuck with these sluggish, old, waterfall, workflows
从 A 到 B 到 C 完全都是提前确定好的
A to B to C, totally predetermined.
因此  寻找更好的软件开发方式新流程
So, the search for new processes to get software made
for better ways
是主要的时间花费
was sort of all consuming at the time
事实上 每个月似乎都有新的开发者
In fact every month, there seemed to be somebody new
对如何改善软件开发的过程提出宏伟的设想
who had a grand vision for how they were going to fix the software development process
其中就有极限编程 有 Kanban 还有统一软件开发过程等
there was Kanban, rational unified process
不胜枚举
the list goes on.
在这些方法论的激烈竞争中
The methodology wars saw a slew of competing new visions
也催生出了新的观点和改进方法
new fixes and that was the scuffle
那就是 Dave Thomas 和他在雪鸟滑雪场的朋友们迫不及待开始探讨的领域
Dave thomas and his buddies up at Snowbird were stepping into
值得让这群人齐声欢呼喝彩的就是《敏捷软件开发宣言》
Their own salvo was something called the manifesto for agile software development.
当时的开发速度正在以前所未有的速度保持增长
The speed of production was ramping up like never before
而开源使开发人员变得更强大
open source had made developers more powerful
另一方面 开发人员也需要一种新的敏捷的开发模式
And, in turn, developers needed a new more agile mode of production.
顺便提一下 那些在雪鸟滑雪场会面的人
The guys who met at Snowbird
在经过一番你来我往的争论后 才确定用这个词
argued a long time before landing on that word by the way
敏捷
agile in the end
这个词非常切题
It was the descriptor that made sense
这种方式就好像国家地理描述大型猫科动物的方式
It's how you describe big cats in National Geographic.
一个与瀑布式开发预设路径正好相反的词
A word that describes the exact opposite of a waterfall's pre ordained path.
随着新的信息层出不穷
As new information came up,
这个词让那些愿意改变航向的人看到了一线曙光
it's a word for people willing to change course on a dime
请注意这可不是一个名词 而是一个形容词
And notice that it's not a noun, it's an adjective.
敏捷更像是一种习惯 而不是一种具体的说辞
Agile would be a mode of being, not a concrete saying.
那么 那些采用敏捷的开发者提供了什么呢
So, what did those agile guys have to offer?
他们的总体解决方案是什么？
What was their big solution?
现在很多人都认为敏捷是一个复杂的集合 包括不同的角色和系统
The agile that many of us know today is a complex set of roles and systems
会有一个项目经理
You've got a scrum master
一个项目团队 产品负责人
a scrum team, a product owner.
同时他们都要进行一到两周的冲刺工作
And they're all going through one or two week sprints of work.
与此同时 工作都堆积在“冰盒”和“沙盒”中
Meanwhile, work is piling up in ice boxes, and sand boxes,
好吧 听起来感觉流程很多
and well, let's say it can feel like a lot of process
但一开始的时候是没有这些流程的
But none of that was there at the beginning
撰写该敏捷宣言的人 目标是简单 和清晰
The guys who wrote that manifesto aimed for simplicity and clarity
实际上 简单是它制胜的法宝
The vision was so simple, in fact
从那时起 它就具有定义几乎每个开发人员命运之路的能力
that it had the power to define the path of almost every developer's destiny from then on.
我们已经提到了 我们更喜欢某种方式而不是另一种方式
We came up with the, we prefer a over b way of expressing the values
事实上 我们就写下了几乎所有的观点
And we actually wrote down pretty much the full values
现在都是敏捷宣言的一部分 在午餐这段时间
that are now part of the manifesto over lunch.
这是可以管理开发的四个奇思妙想
Four big ideas that could govern development
如果你尚且还不熟悉那些敏捷的诫命
In case you don't know those agile commandments by heart
他们会这样解释
they go like this:
个体和互动胜过流程和工档；
Individuals and interactions over processes and tools.
可工作的软件胜过文档；
Working software over comprehensive documentation.
客户协作胜过合同谈判；
Customer collaboration over contract negotiation.
响应变化胜过遵循计划
Responding to change over following a plan.
我记得第一次看到这个宣言时的情形
I remember the first time I encountered the manifesto.
我刚开始学习编程
I was newish to coding
老实说 当时我并没有觉得这个想法有多棒
and to be honest I didn't get what the big deal was.
一直到我了解到那些支持敏捷开发的工具和平台
Until I understood the tools and platforms that make agile work
对我来说 这只是一些模糊的概念
to me, it was just some fuzzy concepts.
但是 对于长期以来一直被这些问题纠缠的开发人员来说
But, for developers who been struggling with these issues for a long time
这是一个很好的行动方案
it was a call to action
该宣言是一盏灯 可以激发更多奇思妙想
the manifesto was designed to be a spark that
could inspire something bigger
这四点宣言和一些支持材料都发布在 Agilemanifesto.org 网站上
These four values and some supporting materialwere posted on a website Agilemanifesto.org
并且呼吁其他开发者签名以表示支持
and they just straight up asked other developers to sign their names to show support
我想我们都惊呆了
i think we're all stunned
很快获得了 1000 个签名 接着 10000 个 然后签名数一直在增长
when we got to a thousand signatures, and then ten thousand then just keep growing and growing and growing
这基本上变成了一场革新运动
and it basically it became a movement
他们从来没有计划过把这份敏捷宣言带出滑雪小屋
It was never their plan to walk out of that ski lodge with a manifesto per se
这只是一群热衷于软件开发的人
They were just a group of people passionate about software development
并且对帮助他人更好地发展充满热情
who felt a kind of evangelical zeal about helping others do development better.
但很明显 “敏捷” 本身像长了腿一样
It became clear though, that agile had legs
红帽公司首席开发倡导者 Burr Sutter
Red Hat's chief developer advocate, Burr Sutter
谈到了“敏捷”对于还困在“瀑布”中的开发人员来说是一种解脱
talks about what a relief agile was for developers trapped under a waterfall
因此 敏捷的概念从根本上引起了人们的共鸣
So, the concept of agile fundamentally resonated with people
基本上是在说：“看 我们专注于人员而不是流程
because it basically said"Look, we focus on people over processes.
我们专注于交互和协作而不是工具和文档
We focus on interactions and collaboration over tools and documentation
我们认为工作软件高于一切
We value working software above all else
我们宁愿人们通过小批量的工作
and we'd rather people work in small batches and
实现高度互动 快速迭代 ”
be highly interactive and highly iterative
而对于一些人来说 这个开发者的革新走得太远
For some, this developers revolution went too far.
敏捷甚至被视为是给那些不负责任的黑客心态的合理说辞
Agile could even be seen as legitimizing an irresponsible hacker mindset
早期反对敏捷最重要的声音之一是 Steve Rakitin
One of the most important voices that spoke out against agile early on was Steve Rakitin
他是一名软件工程师 拥有超过 40 年的行业经验
He's a software engineer with over 40 years experience in the industry.
当他大学毕业时
When he finished college
Rakitin 就开始建造第一个核电站数字控制系统
Rakitin went to work building the first digital control system for nuclear power plants.
几十年来 他一直致力于研发电力软件和医疗设备软件
And for decades he's kept on working on power plant software and software for medical devices
这些都是对安全很注重的软件
Safety-critical software.
没错
So, yeah.
你可以预料到 他可不会对这种手忙脚乱的开发方式感兴趣
You can imagine that this is a guy not so interested in af ly-by-the-seat-of-your-pants-approach.
因此 在方法论战争的尾声 敏捷横空出世
So, when agile came out at the tail end of the methodology wars
Rakitin 对此翻了个白眼
Rakitin sort of rolled his eyes
就像是 “好吧 我们换种方式说
It was like, "well, here we go again, another bunch of people
如同一群人围坐着喝着啤酒
sat around drinking beer and
就想出了开发软件的其他办法 ”
coming up with you know other ideas for developing software
顺便提一下 敏捷宣言中许多已经得到进一步发展
Many of which, by the way
had already been developed and used in
并应用于早期的开发方法里了
some of these earlier methods.
他这么想其实也没有什么错
He wasn't wrong about giving them side eyes either
实际上你可以在 “雪鸟峰会” 前几十年就追溯到敏捷哲学的踪迹 20 世纪 40 年代
You can track back agile-ish philosophies decades before the Snowbird summit
例如 像看板Kanban 这样的精益工作方法可以追溯到四十年代
For example, lean full methodologies like Kanban, go all the way back to the 1940s
当时丰田受到超市货架存货技术的启发…
when toyota got inspired by shelf stocking techniques
at supermarkets..
他们的精益制造理念最终被用于软件开发
Their philosophy for lean manufacturing ended up being repurposed for software development
不过 Rakitin 有另外一个担忧
Rakitin had a whole other concern too
这篇宣言发表时我非常怀疑它
I was very skeptical when this manifesto was published
因为它基本上是为了让软件工程师花更多的时间编写代码
because it basically came across as a way to allow software engineers to spend more time writing code
花更少的时间搞清楚需要做什么
less time figuring out what needs to be done
同时记录文档的时间少了很多
and a lot less time documenting anything.
对于 Rakitin 来说 这不仅仅是提出新的工作流程创意
For Rakitin, this was about more than coming up with new workflow ideas
这也关乎到他职业生涯的清白声誉
It was about the integrity of his profession.
长期以来 软件工程并未被视为正规的工程学科
For a long time, the software engineering was not viewed as aa legitimate engineering discipline.
相比于电气工程和所有其他工程学科
like electrical engineering and all the other engineering disciplines
在我看来 部分原因是因为普遍缺乏软件工程师认可的公认实践
and in my opinion part of the reason was because there was a general lack of accepted practices that software engineers used.
当我们经历了 90 年代的十年 逐渐开始明晰其中的一些流程
As we got through the decade of the nineties and we started identifying some of these processes,
似乎其中一些已经在事实上被实施 而且也很合理
it seemed like some of them were actually starting to take hold, and many of them made a lot of sense.
然后敏捷宣言的出现了
Then comes along the manifesto
如果软件工程将成为正规的工程学科
If software engineering is ever going to become a legitimate engineering discipline,
那么你就需要流程化的东西
you need to process.
其他所有工程学科都有流程
Every other engineering discipline has processes,
为什么软件工程就没有？
why not software?
我是 Saron Yitbarek 你正在收听的是红帽的原创播客代码英雄
i'm Saron Yitbarek and you're listening to command line heroes, an original podcast from red hat
那么 如果我们把在核电站工作的人士的观点放在一边
So, if we leave aside people working at nuclear power plants
转而关注更广阔的企业界
and focus instead on the larger corporate world,
我们发现敏捷已经逐渐广受认可
we find that agile has bit by bit taken over.
但很自然的 也会有一些公司在抵制
But, not without a little corporate resistance naturally
我倾向于认为我们在采用敏捷开发的过程中
I think the greatest resistance that we tend to see
受到的最大阻力来自中高级管理层
in agile adoption comes from senior and middle management.
这位是 Bain＆Company 的合伙人 Darrell Rigby
This is Darrell Rigby, a partner at Bain & Company
他们一直尝试在软件开发公司中推行敏捷开发
They've been experimenting with using agileand software development companies.
不仅如此 还包括产品开发
But, also product development,
新闻服务开发
news service development
广告计划和忠诚度计划等
advertising programs and loyalty programs.
不管他们要做什么
And everywhere they go,
项目管理者都会面临点压力
there's a potential for the managers to
get a little nervous.
敏捷改变了他们的价值
It changes the very notion
of how they believe they add value
因为他们正在逐步退出细节上的管理或干预
because they're moving away from micromanaging, or micro-meddling,
现在团队被赋予权力 对他们加以指导
with these teams to empowering them and coaching them.
现在 敏捷并不能保证阻止中间轻微的干预
Now, agile is no guarantee agains micro-meddlers.
我承认 我第一次看到一个敏捷管理委员会时
I admit the first time I saw an agile management board
我认为这是一个永无止境的待办事项清单
I thought it was just this never ending to-do list.
我有了点压迫感
A bit overwhelming
但后来当我开始真正使用敏捷产品管理工具时
But then I started actually using an agile project management tool
我完全变成了它们的粉丝
and I was blown away.
我是一个编码培训营的新人
I was new out of a coating bootcamp,
我试图弄清楚如何确定功能的优先级并做出产品决策
and I was trying to figure out how to prioritize featuresand make product decisions.
那些看起来很可怕的工具让我有了所有这些想法
that scary-looking tool
然后给它们命名 顺序和结构
forced me to organize all these ideas
and give them names
从而可以帮助我更好地管理我的项目
order, and structure. It helped me manage my project.
所以 我确实同意 Rigby 的观点
So, I do take Rigby's point.
有些人可能会看到这些工具产生的影响并认为
Some people might look at the effect of tools like that and think,
如果敏捷赋予开发人员权力
If agile empowers developers,
那么就会剥夺经理们的管理权
then it must disempower their managers.
但是 它的价值比任何一个职位都要大
But, this was larger than any one job title.
敏捷开发的发展势如破竹
Agile's forward momentum was growing.
更重要的是
And more importantly,
它正在证明自己
agile was proving itself.
目前 成千上万的团队已经采用敏捷开发
Agile has been used by tens of thousands of teams at this point.
因此 我们有大量数据能够说明在哪里可以采用敏捷的方式
So, we've got a lot of great data on where agile can be used
答案是 无论何时你开始创新
The answer is, any time you're thinking about doing innovation
相比你现在使用的方式 敏捷团队能更好实现目标
an agile team can probably do it better than the way you're doing it today.
有许多更大的 知名的公司都在变革自身
There are a lot of bigger, well known companies that have transformed to themselves.
亚马逊是敏捷方法的重要用户
Amazon is a big user of agile approaches.
奈飞 Facebook 和 Salesforce - 他们都是敏捷的重度用户
Netflix, Facebook, and Salesforce all of them heavy users of agile
实际上敏捷方法不仅重新定义了工作方式
and it has really not just redefined the way they work
更是重新定义了行业的运作方式
but the way the industry works
当 Rigby 第一次听说敏捷 时
When Rigby first heard about agile
他认为这是一种奇怪的语言
he thought it was just a weird language
他当时正在与许多大型零售商的 IT 部门合作
he was working with the IT departments at a lot of big retailers
无意间听到他们谈论 “time boxes” “sprint”
And he kept hearing them talk about time boxes and sprints and
和 “scrum master”
scrum masters.
起初 他并不懂他们在说什么
At first, he didn't have a clue what they were talking about
他告诉我他实际上是试图忽略任何有关敏捷的字眼
He told me he actually tried to ignore any mention of agile
就像这是他不需要学习的另一种语言
like it was another language he didn't have to learn after all
毕竟 他本人不是开发人员
he wasn't a developer himself
但是如今 他却成为了敏捷信徒
Today, he's such a believer
把敏捷带到他的家里
that he's literally brought agile to his home
带入他的教堂
and into his church
我不一定每天早上都和家人坐在一起
I do not necessarily sit down with my family every morning
和他们一起参加敏捷开发式的会议
and have a scrum meeting with them
但是 我已经非常擅长为我要做的事情排优先级
But I have become very good at prioritizing the things that i'm going to do
十多年来 敏捷已经从边缘走向主流
Agile has gone from fringe to mainstream in just over a decade
但是 企业认同还是有代价的
But the corporate assimilation came at a cost
在某些情况下
And in some cases,
这种同化甚至会使敏捷宣言的最初意图变得模糊
that assimilation even met bastardizing the manifesto's original intentions.
Dave Thomas 让我想起了这一点
Dave Thomas reminded me of that.
他说 当他和其他 16 位雪鸟会议上的伙伴第一次写下宣言时
He says that when he and those 16 other Snowbird guys
first wrote it,
根本没有既定的指示
there was no real prescription at all.
因此 即使宣言中没有告诉你如何应用这些条例
So even though the manifesto doesn't tell you how to apply the values,
我猜想你已经对大概会发生什么
I'm assuming you had some idea of what you thought would happen
还有人们会怎么做 有一些大概的思路了吧？
or what people would do with it
老实说啊 我还真没有
Honestly, I did not.
听到这里 你可能会感到惊讶 因为敏捷现在看起来很有说服力
This might surprise you. Agile can seem so prescriptive today.
有书籍 认证 工具 课程和产品的整个市场
There's a whole marketplace of books, certifications, tools, courses and products that
向你展示如何“实现敏捷”
show you how to "do agile".
尽管有成千上万的手册和专业人士想要向你展示“唯一真理”
But despite the thousands of manuals and professionals who want to show you the one drew way
Dave Thomas 表示 他们却错过了重点
Dave Thomas says they're really missing the whole point
实际上它是一组价值观
It's a set of values
我想这就像黄金法则
It's like the golden rule, I guess. It's like
你知道 如果你要做一些邪恶恶毒的事情 你会想 “好吧
you know, if you're about to do something evil and vicious you think, "okay,
如果有人这样做 我又怎么会喜欢”
how would I like it if someone did that to me."
你知道吗 这种场合也适合用黄金法则
You know? The golden rule applies. Well it's the same with this
好吧 敏捷宣言也是如此
the agia manifesto.
它并没有告诉你该做什么 不该做什么
It's not telling you what to do, and what not to do,
它只是告诉你 你做的一切是否符合这个价值观
it's just telling you how to assess whether or not what you do is in line with that kind of way of doing things.
是的 我想只要回到敏捷软件开发宣言的名称
Yep. I think that just going back to that name of manifesto for agile software development,
真正脱颖而出并且经久不衰的一个词
the one word that really stands out and that has been very persistent,
也是人们真正关注的就是“敏捷”
and people really latched onto is the word agile.
那么现在使用“敏捷”这个词又出了什么问题呢
What is wrong with the use of the word agile today?
“敏捷”这个词的问题在于
The problem with the word agile is that,
在我们刚开始提出的时候
in the title that we came up with
它是描述软件开发的形容词
it is an adjective that describes software development.
但接下来人们就产生了疑问：“我该怎么着手实施敏捷呢？”
But what happens then is that people say, "How do I do this agile thing?"
突然之间 涌出了一大批咨询顾问
Suddenly, out of the wood work springs a whole army of consultants, and consultancies
他们看到了 极限编程 的成功
who look at the success of XP,
看到了宣言的成功 “嘿
look at the success of the manifesto and say, "Hey,
那里有座金山 ”
there's gold in them there hills."
然后就开始告诉人们如何“做敏捷”
So, they start telling people how to "do agile."
这是一个问题
that is a problem
因为你不能“做”敏捷
because you can't do agile.
敏捷不是你要“做”的事情
Agile's not what you do,
而是你如何做事情的方式
it's how you do it.
然而 有些公司会乐意卖给你敏捷相关的套装
And yet, there are companies out there who will happily sell you agile in a box
我觉得这很讽刺
That, I think, is a travesty.
这里的咨询就好像是进入一家财富 1000 强企业
The consult that go into a Fourteen 1,000 company
然后帮助他们设定“敏捷”
and help them set up "agile".
然后带走了 500 万美元 你懂吗？
They're walking away with five million dollars you know
太棒了 钱真好赚
great good for them
但是 现实情况是
But, the reality is that,
这就像告诉要老虎如何变得敏捷一样
that's like telling a tiger to be agile
说：“先走七步 然后左脚迈出来
by saying, "take seven steps and then spring off your left foot,
然后再走两步 然后迈出右脚”
and then take two more steps, and spring off your right foot."
嗯 实际上只有瞪羚做同样的事情 这才会是有用的
All right well that only works if the gazelle is doing the same thing.
你猜怎么着？没有人告诉瞪羚这样做
And guess what no one's told the gazelle to be agile that way
瞪羚基本都会跑到地平线尽头上大笑起来
It's basically running off to the horizon laughing as it's horns off
因为老虎在“邯郸学步”
because the tiger's gone the wrong way.
当你告诉团队如何敏捷时 会发生同样的事情
Same thing happens when you tell a team how to be agile.
如果你对他们说
If you say to them
“这是你必须遵循的规则
"Here are the rules you have to follow,
然后他们唯一能做的就是跟随职责
here is the processes you have to follow," then the last thing they have is a duty
因为他们已被设定好该执行的程序
because they have been boxed into a particular path.
管理层将根据他们服从原则或程序的程度
Management is going to be judging them based on how well they follow those principles, or those procedures.
而不是开发软件的水平来判断表现如何
Not on how well they're developing software.
所以 回顾一下
So, looking back,
宣言发布之前和之后的开发者的角色
when you think about the role of the developer before the manifesto, and then now after the manifesto,
是如何因为你的宣言本身改变或扩展的呢
how has the role of the developer changed, or expanded, because of what you wrote?
我认为大多数程序员都能理解到关键点 这值得肯定
To their credit, I think that the majority of program was out there to get it.
我觉得敏捷宣言给了许多开发人员按照这种方法去做的授权
I think that the manifesto has empowered a lot of developers to start following practices that,
某种程度上是他们以前就知道该如何
to some extent, they knew they should have been doing,
但从来没有权利这样做
but they never really had the authority to do.
像测试收集反馈
Things like testing, for example,
缩短迭代周期之类的事情
gathering feedback, short iterations
因此 在许多方面 工作变得更有趣 更充实
So, in many ways, the job is more interesting and more fulfilling.
同时我认为 程序员也可能会感到有点害怕
I think, also programmers are feeling a little bit more scared
因为现在他们有了责任
because now they have responsibility
过去 他们只是遵循命令 这个程序不起作用？
in the old days, I was just following orders and why doesn't this program work
好吧 但我遵循了规范
while I followed the spec
而如今 程序员肩负着责任
Whereas nowadays, it's on your shoulders
所以 我觉得这个职业因敏捷宣言而有所成长
So, I think the job has grown up a bit because of the manifesto.
我认为人们开始意识到
I think people are going to realize
他们对自己所开发东西负有点对点的责任
that they have an end to end responsibility for what they deliver.
敏捷取得了如此广泛得成功
The success of agile has been so pervasive,
改变了工作流程和态度
that its altering workflow
远远超出了开发者世界的范畴
and attitudes far beyond the development world
当然也超越了雪鸟会议召开的小木屋
certainly beyond the snowbird lodge
我们不禁要问
We have to ask,
“相比于 2001 年撰写宣言时 今天成为敏捷开发人员意味着什么？”
"What does it even mean to be an agile developer today versus 2001 when the manifesto was written?"
最初的敏捷精神是否仍然存在？
Does the original spirit of agile persist?
如果确实发生了变化 这是一件坏事吗？
And if it did change, is that such a bad thing?
对于谷歌的多元化业务合作伙伴 Ruha Devanesan 来说
For Ruha Devanesan, a diversity business partner at Google,
敏捷的思维方式
the agile mindset
可能已经发展到影响公平性和在工作场所中的平等性了
might have evolved to the point where it's now influencing basic levels of fairness and workplace equality.
让团队具有包容性的部分原因
Part of what makes teams inclusive
是他们在进行非常基础的工作时 可以评价和反思自己
is their ability to evaluate and reflect on how they work together on a very fundamental level
当大多数团队一起工作时
And most teams, when they work together,
没有足够的动力停下来思考
They don't have space to stop and think
他们团队宗旨
about their team dynamics, about
是否每个人都在能桌上发表意见
whether everyone's having a voice at the table,
关于是否有人在推动其他人
about whether someone's steam rolling someone else. Or
或者是否有人在一直都保持沉默 如果他们保持沉默
whether someone is silent the entire time. And if they are silent,
为什么他们保持沉默？
why are they silent?
因此 在考虑包容性时
and so when thinking about inclusion
我认为敏捷团队使用的一些工具在为团队创建架构
I thought that some of the tools that agile teams use could be very useful
或更具包容性的框架方面非常有用
in giving teams a structure, or a framework to be more inclusive
所以多样性包括性别 种族
So diversity not just in terms of gender, and race, and ethnicity,
还有功能多样性
but also functional diversity.
功能多样性为团队带来了复杂性
And functional diversity introduces complexity into a team.
但是 我们在这里要声明他们的不同
But, let's make a distinction here.
Ruha 并不是说敏捷就等于多样性
Ruha is not saying that agile equals diversity
她的意思是 “敏捷加多样性等于更好的团队 ”
She's saying, "Agile plus diversity equals better teams."
Ruha 的想法在她写的一篇名为
Ruha's ideas were crystallized in an article
《论通过敏捷方法解锁多样性》的文章中得到了体现
she wrote called, Can agile methodology unlocked diversity
我们将在演示笔记中添加一个链接 — 这可是值得一读的文章
will throw a link in our show notes it's worth read
在这篇文章中 她会引导你去了解
In it, she walks you through this idea that
多元化不仅仅是人力资源部门一直在谈论的模糊概念
diversity isn't just a fuzzy concept your HR department keeps talking about.
这里提供了一个强有力的商业案例
It's actually a strong business case here.
多样性可以与敏捷相辅相成
Diversity can dovetail with agile.
这篇介绍复杂性的文章
So, that introduction of complexity
最终目的是让大家从不同的角度看待你的结果或产品
for the end goal of having an outcome or a product that has been looked at for many angles
我们持有的是基本同样的观点
That's the same fundamental point of view that we
take when we say
当我们说为团队增加多样性可以带来更好的结果
adding diversity to a team leads to a good outcome
带来更多的创新和创造力时
leads to more innovation and more creativity
因为当你从多个角度去看待并协作解决工作中的问题时
because when you have multiple perspectives looking at a problem helping to do problem solving work
你更有可能得出一个更好的结果
you're more likely to come out with an outcome that is more robust.
甚至可以对日常会议这样简单的事情
Even something as simple as a daily stand-up,
团队中的每个人反馈时
where everybody on your team gets to report
会让内向的人或其他不爱说话的人发表自己的见解
is going to give voice to introverts or other people who have a hard time being heard.
我真正喜欢敏捷的原因是
The thing I really like about agile is
有一些内置的机制来帮助团队停下来进行思考
it has some built-in mechanisms to help teams stop and reflect.
这可能是因为敏捷开发是如此之快
And that may be because agile is so quick,
并且有为时两周的冲刺任务 如果你没有建立这些机制
and with two weeks sprints, if you don't build in those mechanisms
你可能会偏离轨道 没法再回到正轨
you're likely to go way off track and not have the consciousness to come back on to track
因为让大家都能提出工作反馈
reflection on how we're working together
并借此不断改善
how can we course correct
这是团队能够包容的基本表现
is one of the fundamental ways in which teams can be inclusive
既然我们谈论的是包容性
Since we're talking about inclusivity
现在可能是指出那些敏捷宣言的 17 位创始人的好时机
now might be a good time to point out that those seventeen founders of the agile manifesto
是的…他们都是白人
yeah ... They were all white men.
实际上那个房间没有多样性
There was zero diversity in that room.
这是对该组织的一种非常普遍的批评
And that is a very common criticism of the group.
而且我对此深表同情
And one that I have a lot of sympathy with.
如果敏捷宣言创始人采用了这些敏捷原则
if the manifesto founders use those agile principles,
并将其应用于他们自己的会议
and apply it to their own meeting
那么他们可能在完成部分工作后 会问他们自己
they may have gotten part way done and ask themselves
“嘿 你注意到我们没有邀请任何女性参加这次会议吗？”
"Hey, did you notice we didn't invite any women to this meeting?"
我在想会不会有一个有色人种会持有不同意见
I wonder if a person of color would have a different opinion.
物以类聚 人以群分
people's friends tend to be and look like they
like they do.
所以 如果考虑敏捷宣言的第一个人是白人
So, if the first person that thought about
the agile manifesto was a white guy
他邀请到桌上的人也是白人也就不足为奇了
it's not surprising that the people he invited to the table were also white guys.
我们有机会停下来说：“让我们退后一步
But, we have an opportunity to stop and say, "Let's take a step back, let's expand
让我们扩大我们的视野 寻找我们现在拥有的关系网络之外的人
our lens and look for people outside of the network that I currently have,
谁可以带来不同的视角并帮助我们更好地改进这种开发方式”
who can bring a different perspective and help me elevate this methodology to something even better."
对我来说这很有道理 因为敏捷开发正是如此 … 好吧 敏捷
It makes sense to me that because agile is so ... well, so, agile,
我们可以将它应用于不同的问题和行业
we can apply it to different problems and industries,
敏捷的应用方面
The application of agile,
以及其在现实生活中出现时候的样子
and what it looks like in real life,
是不断变化 不断扩展的 我想它正在将宣扬的内容付诸实践
is constantly shifting, expanding. I guess it's practicing what it preaches.
没有最正确的答案
There is no settled answer,
没有最后的终点
no subtler end point.
这是我们有时会忘记的事情：硬规则是敏捷的敌人
That's something we sometimes forget: Hard rules are the enemy of agility.
因此 如果一个敏捷团队告诉你
So, if an agile team ever tells you that
你敏捷的一部分意味着你必须每两周开发一个新的版本
part of being agile means you have to produce
a new release every two weeks
或者你必须做什么事
or you have to do this, or you have to do that,
那么 根据定义 这可不是敏捷
then, by definition, that's not agile.
你老是说“总是” 你也不再是敏捷了
The second you say "always," you aren't being agile anymore.
那些在犹他州雪鸟会议碰面的 17 名男子
Those 17 men who met in Snowbird, Utah
最后宣称成立敏捷联盟
eventually dubbed themselves the Agile Alliance.
该联盟成为一个非营利组织
That alliance became a nonprofit,
每年都举办一次会议
and that non profit started hosting a conference every year
这个联盟的成长和发展
It's grown and grown
催生了更多全新的理论和方法
spawning whole new theories and methodologies
这正是我感觉非常有趣的东西
and here's something I think is super interesting
在 2008 年的会议上
At the 2008 conference,
比利时开发人员 Patrick Debois 参加了并开始引领一条道路
Belgium developer, Patrick Debois attends and sets off down a path
他发明了一种全新的软件开发实践 DevOps
that leads him to inventing a whole new practice of software development DevOps
我从未想到与敏捷的一系列原则与 DevOps 和整个行业是都紧密相关
I'd never thought that agile a set of principles and DevOps a whole industry were related
但是 现在我在想
But now I am thinking,
“敏捷的兴起与 DevOps 的发明之间有多少关联？
"How strong really is that line between the rise of agile and the invention of DevOps?
一个突破是否孕育了另一个突破？”我们会一起去探索
Did the one breakthrough lead to the other organically?" We're gonna find out together
因为我们的下一集是正是 DevOps
because our next episode is all DevOps
对！一整集的内容
All episode long
会在两周内推出
and it's dropping in two weeks
《代码英雄》是红帽的原创播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
有关我们的播客和其他更多信息
For more information about this and past episodes,
请访问 Redhat.com/commandlineheroes 在那里
go to RedHat.com/commandlineheroes Once you're there,
你也可以关注我们的消息订阅
you can also sign up for our newsletter.
想要免费听取最新内容
And to get new episodes delivered automatically for free
请订阅我们的节目
make sure to subscribe to the show.
也可以搜索 “Command Line Heroes”
Just search for "Command Line Heroes" in
在 Apple Podcast Spotify  Google Play CastBox 中都有
Apple podcasts, Spotify,  Google Play, CastBox
然后点击“订阅” 你将在第一时间获得我们的内容更新
or however you get your podcast then hit subscribe so you'll be the first to know when new episodes are available
我是 Saron Yitbarek 感谢收听 请坚持编程
I'm siranyat barack thanks for listening and keep on coden